It's not a felony if you're doing it for the good guys.
American Made is a action, comedy, crime film directed by Doug Liman.
The true story of pilot Barry Seal, who transported contraband
for the CIA and the Medellin cartel in the 1980s.
Barry Seal, played by Tom Cruise.
Monty 'Schafer', played by Domhnall Gleeson.
Lucy Seal, played by Sarah Wright.
Sheriff Downing, played by Jesse Plemons.
JB, played by Caleb Landry Jones.
Judy Downing, played by Lola Kirke.
American Made is a 2017 American action comedy film directed by Doug Liman, written by Gary Spinelli and starring Tom
Cruise, Domhnall Gleeson, Sarah Wright, Alejandro Edda, Mauricio Mejía, Caleb Landry Jones and Jesse Plemons.
It is inspired by the life of Barry Seal, a former TWA pilot who became a drug smuggler for the
Medellín Cartel in the 1980s and then, to avoid jail time, became an informant for the DEA.
The film was first released in Taiwan on August 18, 2017, and
then in the United States on September 29, 2017.
It is the first film directed by Liman to be released by Universal Pictures since The
Bourne Identity in 2002 and played in 2D and IMAX in select theaters.
It grossed $134 million worldwide and received generally positive
reviews from critics, who praised Cruise's performance.
The film explores themes of central intelligence agency (cia), drug
smuggling, money laundering, pilot, based on true story.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.